http://www.api.org/privacy

Pipelines
Pipeline Strategic Data Tracking System (PSDTS)
Alaska - a State of Energy
What is Fracking?
Energy Primers
What is Fracking?
Why is fracking for natural gas important?
What’s the difference between wastewater disposal and “fracking”?
What chemicals are used in fracking?
What are alternatives to make fracking less impactful?
I’ve heard that hydraulic fracturing is linked to cancer. Is that true?
How much water does hydraulic fracturing use?
How is groundwater protected during hydraulic fracturing?
Does fracking cause flaming water faucets?
How many jobs has the oil and natural gas industry created?
Does hydraulic fracturing cause earthquakes?
What are fracking myths?
Natural gas is alternative energy
What are the claims of anti-fracking activists?
What does EPA say about water contamination?
Menu
Browse Global Industry Services (GIS)
19B Perforator
Center for Offshore Safety (COS)
Individual Certifications & Training
Individual Cert. Programs (ICP)
Products & Services
Individual Cert. Programs (ICP)
Important - Fraud Alert
Engine Oil (EOLCS)
Products & Services
Engine Oil (EOLCS)
Application and Fees
Licensee Directory
Unauthorized Use of API Marks
Categories / Classifications
Engine Oil (EOLCS)
Documents
Diesel Exhaust Fluid (DEF)
Products & Services
Diesel Exhaust Fluid (DEF)
Application and Fees
Licensee Directory
DEF Locator
Motor Oil Matters (MOM)
General Statement of Privacy
API is committed to respecting your privacy.  This privacy policy describes the information we collect from you, and how we use, share and protect that information.
Automatic Collection of Information
Our web servers automatically capture certain information including, but not limited to, your IP address or mobile device identifier, the domain name of the web page from which you entered our site, the pages that you visit on our site, the click-through rates, and the amount of time that you spend here. However, this information does not identify you to us. We may use and analyze this data for analytics, trends and to improve our site. If we share any of this information with third parties, it will be provided in aggregate form only so that it does not identify any individual user.
Information You Provide
If you request information from API or engage in similar activities on this website, you may be required to submit personal information to API. This information will include data such as your name and contact information that is needed to respond to your inquiries. If you choose not to provide the information that is requested by API, you may continue to visit the site, but you may be unable to access certain offers, services or secure pages.
Content You Provide
To the extent that the website provides any bulletin boards or other open forums, you understand and agree that API is not responsible for any information that you provide on these platforms and recognize that others may collect and use any information that you provide.
How We Use Information
We use your information to respond to requests for information you may provide to us; to inform you about our services and relevant information in the industries we serve; to let you know about events; or for other purposes with your consent.
How We Share Information
API may share your information with service providers and vendors that help us administer this site and respond to inquiries, but these service providers and vendors are not permitted to use your data for any purpose unrelated to providing these services.  We also may share your information with trusted third parties for limited purposes.
API also may provide personal information to law enforcement authorities or otherwise when API believes that this release of information is necessary: (1) to comply with legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) to protect and defend the rights or property of API and its members and customers; or (3) to protect the other users of the site or the public.
If we make a sale or transfer of assets, or are otherwise involved in a merger or transfer, we may transfer your information to one or more third parties as part of that transaction.  Finally, in addition to the sharing described in this privacy policy, we may share information about you with other third parties when you consent to such sharing.
Privacy with Respect to Minors
API does not knowingly collect or use information from children under the age of 16 without the consent of a parent or guardian, except as permitted by law.
Cookies and “Do Not Track” Signals
When you visit our website, we may place a cookie on your computer that will allow us to track your visit to our site and help us to improve the site. Cookies are files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings on your device.
Our website is not designed to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our websites.
Other Websites and Links
This website contains links to other websites and may provide integration with social media platforms. If you choose to use any of these links or this integration, you will be leaving the API website and going to a website that is not controlled by us. Protection of your privacy at these linked sites will be governed by the privacy policy at that site. You should take the time to read the privacy policies at these sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites or the use of any information that you provide.
Security
We use physical, technical and administrative measures to protect your information against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification.  While we strive to protect the information we maintain, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us since no method of data transmission or storage is 100% secure.
Email
It is your right to stop receiving email any time you choose and to only receive relevant and wanted email communications. You can unsubscribe from our email list at any time and for any reason by clicking on the unsubscribe list on any email you have received from us.
European Visitors
Legal Grounds.  We will process your personal data (1) with your consent; (2) to perform a contract between you and us, such as a request for information; (3) to comply with a legal obligation; or (4) where we have a legitimate interest to do so, including responding to your requests.
Retention.  We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected and processed, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, accounting or reporting requirements.  We generally retain data for three years, unless we have legitimate grounds to retain it for a longer period of time.  In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case it is no longer personal data.  Upon expiration of the applicable retention period we will securely destroy your personal data in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.
International Users
The information you submit to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of our website may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States. U.S. law may offer different levels of protection for information than may be available in your country. By using this website, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information.
Changes to Policy
This policy may change over time. Your continued use of the site after these changes are posted constitutes your agreement to the changes with regard to information collected.
Related Topics:
Natural Gas & Oil
Products & Services
Policy & Issues
Other Resources:
American Energy Works
API WorkSafe
Center for Offshore Safety
